On April 16, 2016 A Devastating 7.8 Earthquake Struck The Nation Of Ecuador
The Devastation Of The School In The Indigenous Community Of San Salvador De Los Chachis
One major casualty of the earthquake was the bilingual educational complex
in the Chachi indigenous community of San Salvador located deep within the Mache-Chindul rainforest
This was the main primary and secondary school for the community and its areas,
providing education for more than 300 students.
The community was shattered by its loss.
Since the destruction of the school threatened not only the education of the children,
but also the very future of the community itself.
The Devastation Of The School In The Indigenous Community Of San Salvador De Los Chachis
Prophet T.B. Joshua Chartered A Cargo Plane With 20 Tonnes Of Relief Aid For Ecuador
The essential food and hygiene items had been bought in Columbia by T.B. Joshua and the Emmanuel TV Partners,
specifically to meet the needs of the earthquake victims.
The Emmanuel TV Team Prepare The Relief Aid And Load The Cargo Plane
The Cargo Plane Takes Off From Bogota, Colombia And Lands in Quito, Ecuador
The cargo plane was received in Quito, Equador, and then two large trucks provided by the Armed Forces
transported the goods to the Emmanuel TV Operations Centre in the Esmeraldas Province,
close to the areas most affected by the earthquake.
The Aid Is Unloaded And Transported By The Ecuador Military To The Relief Camps
The Emmanuel TV Team With Local Volunteers Prepare The Relief Aid Packages For Distribution
The team worked with local volunteers to pack and then to personally distribute
the much needed supplies, together with fresh fruits and vegetables,
to official Government Shelter Camps in various communities.
The Emmanuel TV Team Distribute The Relief Aid Packages In Government Shelters In Ecuador
During this programme, the Governor of Esmeraldas, Paola Cabezas,
told the Emmanuel TV team about the Chachi Community of San Salvador,
who had received very little help due to their remote location within the rainforest.
Ecuador Charity
The Emmanuel TV team immediately made plans to go there,
taking with them over 2 tonnes of the essential relief aid
as well as emergency water purification kits for each family.
Ecuador Charity
Emmanuel TV Team Make Their Way To Indigenous Community Of San Salvador de Los Chachis
The San Salvador community was indeed difficult to reach,
with all the relief items having to be transported by canoe.
Emmanuel TV Team Make Their Way To Indigenous Community Of San Salvador de Los Chachis
Many of the Emmanuel TV team with local helpers, also had to walk for around two hours to reach San Salvador.
In many places the trail was very muddy.
Emmanuel TV Team Make Their Way To Indigenous Community Of San Salvador de Los Chachis
On arrival, the local community helped unload the canoes
and prepare for the distribution of the family hygiene boxes and the food.
Emmanuel TV Team Make Their Way To Indigenous Community Of San Salvador de Los Chachis
The Emmanuel TV Team Distribute Relief Aid Packages To Members Of The Chachi Community
The community all gathered together to receive the family hygiene boxes and the food aid,
encouraged and happy to know that they had not been forgotten.
During their visit, the Emmanuel TV Team saw that the children were no longer able to go to school
and arranged some games and activities for them.
The Emmanuel TV Team Do Recreational Activities With The Children Whose School Was Destroyed
Later some students, parents and teachers from the school explained more.
Jose Gabriel Tapuya de la Cruz - Student from 'Juan Lorenzo Anapa' School
I am in the 9th grade and I am 19 years old.
The school collapsed due to the earthquake on the 16th of April, 2016
As students, we were not able to continue studying because it was very dangerous.
Luis San Nicolas - Teacher from 'Juan Lorenzo Anapa' School
Currently, I am working in this school as a teacher of History and Geography.
We never expected such a natural disaster but unfortunately, everything has been destroyed.
So, as teachers, we have built temporary classrooms to be able to continue teaching.
We did this because the Ministry of Education made a law that the teaching should continue.
Karely Chasim - 16 years old / 11th Grade
I want to be a lawyer.
To come to school, we have to walk about one hour and a half.
Sometimes, when it rains, it is more difficult because of the mud.
Arriving in a school that is not in proper conditions to study is also very disappointing.
Moreover, we are worried about our uniforms getting wet or dirty.
My name is Adriana Andreína de la Cruz. I live in this community, San Salvador de Los Chachis.
I have three children - two boys and one girl.
One of them is in year 2 and the other one in year 1 of primary school.
When the earthquake happened, the classrooms collapsed and the walls fell down;
now our children don't have anywhere to study. These are not proper conditions for them to study.
When it rains, the temporary classrooms get flooded and the children are not fine there.
As a mother, I am very concerned because I want my children to study in a proper school.
Agustín Anapa Tapuyo - Director of 'Juan Lorenzo Anapa' School
This institution has about 310 students.
Right now, we are in crisis due to the earthquake which has severely damaged the school building.
This school is very important because everything depends on education.
Both children and the youth can make it in life with education.
Education forms them every day; as their character is formed, they serve their nation.
The Emmanuel TV Team Invite An Architect To Survey The Damage Done To The School
Moved by this tragedy, Emmanuel TV quickly arranged for a top Equadorian architect
to visit the site, where he observed the damage and the poor quality of construction.
The Emmanuel TV Team Invite An Architect To Survey The Damage Done To The School
The Architect Draws Plans For A Brand New School Sponsored By Prophet T.B. Joshua
Following the visit, the architect and his team drew up comprehensive plans
for a much improved replacement school.
The Architect Draws Plans For A Brand New School Sponsored By Prophet T.B. Joshua
For the community leaders, this was a dream come true.
They expressed their thanks and commitment to help the project succeed.
The project is for a school of approximately 300 children, distributed as follows:
50 children in kindergarten, 200 in primary school and 50 in secondary school.
To fulfill these needs, we are proposing building 14 classrooms:
2 for kindergarten, 10 for primary and 2 for secondary education.
Moreover, we propose a computer room and science laboratories for Physics and Chemistry.
We are also planning to build a library, administrative office and staff room for teachers.
T.B. Joshua joined with the Emmanuel TV Partners and wasted no time
in agreeing to pay for this major construction project.
On hearing of the Emmanuel TV plan to rebuild the school,
one of the men from the village also spoke on behalf of the community.
Santiago De La Cruz Anapa - Representative Of The Chachi Community
I am joined by the Governor, School Director and other elders of The Chachi Community
The entire community is very happy to see that a dream is about to become reality.
This dream of having in the community an educational institution in line with
the development of the modernisation of education and society in the world today.
To guarantee the execution of this proposal, the entire community through an assembly
resolved to undertake this serious commitment to collaborate with the Emmanuel TV Team
with the transportation of materials in canoes, on donkeys and horses and with the labour
necessary for the project according to our possibilities.
We are sure that thanks to you, T.B. Joshua,
our children, grandchildren, brethren and the coming generations will receive
education in suitable classrooms, with space for research
to strengthen the educational process.
The community of San Salvador De Los Chachis
is located in the heart of the ecological reserve Mache-Chindul.
However, this doesn't signify that we don't have the right to receive quality education
in the infrastructure like the one you (T.B. Joshua) will provide for us.
For the first time in our history, this project is something that has fallen from Heaven to earth.
All our community members are going to work in this project.
Don't expect that only the architect and the Emmanuel TV Team will do the work.
The Chachi community is also going to collaborate with
both the transportation of the materials and coming together to build all the classrooms.
T.B. Joshua, thank you very much!
For us, it is so exciting to have a new school building
because before, we didn't have a school of such quality,
and if Emmanuel TV is giving us the opportunity to have it, we are ready to receive it.
Thank you very much to the organisation, Emmanuel TV.
I am very grateful and thank Emmanuel TV because you are doing us a great favour.
This year, I finished my secondary education, and I want my children to finish as well,
so they can make it in life and I will continue motivating them.
With this new school, we will not have headaches due to the heat; if it rains, we will not get wet
so we will be able to learn better. Thank you, Emmanuel TV!
I appreciate you so much with all my heart. Thank you for what you are doing.
I am very happy and joyful to receive this great gift from you.
The Community Of San Salvador De Los Chachis In The Mache Chindul Ecological Reserve
Although the land for the school belongs to the Chachi community,
the school itself is a government school
and the Emmanuel TV team had important discussions with politicians and officials
before the construction work began.
The Emmanuel TV Team Present The School Project To The Ministry Of Social Inclusion
Jorge Glas - Vice President of the Republic of Ecuador - discusses the School Construction Project with the Emmanuel TV Team and officials of the Ministry of Education.
My name is Carlos Bernal.
I am the Secretary of the Reconstruction Committee of the Republic of Ecuador
after the earthquake of the 16th of April.
I would like to thank you for your cooperation.
We really need your help and we appreciate it.
We are coordinating all through the official channels of the government.
We greatly appreciate your contribution to the school
because we are very concious of the needs of this commuinity.
The Construction Work Begins For The School For Earthquake Victims Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
The local Chachi community starts by demolishing most of the severely damaged school buildings,
preparing the way for the construction work to begin.
The Construction Work Begins For The School For Earthquake Victims Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
Later on in the process, the final two of the old school classrooms are also demolished.
Education is the means of empowering people to take control of their own lives,
as learning how to learn is one of life's most important skills.
Education is to give us success.
It is a rare privilege to send someone to school; to contribute to someone's future.
And Emmanuel TV has the privilege of contributing to the future of generations from the Chachi community
and other farming settlements along the river.
Today, the first materials will be going up the river, ready to start the construction.
Marcelo San Nicolas De La Cruz - President of Parents Association Of The School
These are all the materials that will be transported to San Salvador by canoe.
This is the gasoline for the boats and this is the food for the workers.
This is the sand in bags and these are the rocks that we are carrying to San Salvador.
I give thanks to Emmanuel TV for supporting our community
and for giving us this opportunity that we never had before. Thank you very much!
The Building Materials Are Loaded Into The Canoes For The School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
The Emmanuel TV Team Take the Materials By Canoe To San Salvador De Los Chachis
It soon became clear that the large amounts of material needed to be transported more quickly
for the start of the construction and so a huge truck delivered stones to be transferred to smaller trucks,
which were trying to cross the river to get closer to San Salvador.
Unloading The Stones For Construction Which Will Be Transported To The Community
The Construction Materials Are Transported By Truck To The Community Over Rough Terrain
The river crossing proved to be a challenge but with extra muscle power being provided
by the local community, the truck finally made it.
The Construction Materials Are Transported By Truck To The Community Over Rough Terrain
Other sections of the track were improved by laying stones to help the truck's tyres grip.
Then there was a major breakthrough: Because of the commitment of Emmanuel TV to the school project,
the government provided heavy machinery to clear the track all the way to San Salvador.
This meant that on the few days that were dry enough,
the vehicles carrying the materials for the school construction could drive all the way.
The Construction Materials Are Transported By Truck To The Community Over Rough Terrain
The Construction Work Begins On The School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua As Foundations Are Laid
With sufficient materials now delivered, the construction work began.
Emmanuel TV Team Continues The Construction Of The School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
The Students Of The Community Show Their Appreciation To The Emmanuel TV Team
Once Made, The Bricks Are Loaded Into The Canoes To Transport To The Community
As The Bricks Arrive In The Community, The Building Of The School Walls Begins
Emmanuel TV Team Continues The Construction Of The School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
With the construction work progressing each day in the Chachi community, the school begins to take shape.
As Prophet T.B. Joshua says, we make a living by what we get, we make a life by what we give.
Emmanuel TV Team Continues The Construction Of The School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
Construction Continues At The School Sponsored By Prophet T.B. Joshua
Local Children Play Nearby The Construction Site Of Their New School
Despite The Rain, Work Continues To Complete The School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
Construction Continues At The School Sponsored By Prophet T.B. Joshua
Students Look On With Anticipation As The Construction Of The School Continues
The only thing remaining is to finish the flooring, next week.
In one month, we think we will finish the job completely.
Overview Of The Newly Constructed School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
Finishing Touches Being Applied To the Newly Constructed School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua
Temporary Classrooms Used By Students Awaiting the School's Completion
Overview Of The Newly Constructed School Sponsored By T.B. Joshua